# Alessandro Pezzato

#### INDEPENDENT SOFTWARE CONSULTANT AND TRAINER

Trebaseleghe, PD, Italy

🗷 alessandro@pezzato.net | 👑 1986 | 🛠 alepez.dev | 🖸 alepez | 💖 alepez | 📓 alessandro-pezzato | 🗖 alessandropezzato

"Learn. Code. Teach. Repeat."

### Summary.

With 18+ years of software development experience and a passion for programming since age 11, I bring extensive expertise.

Specializing in C++ since 2007, I consistently deliver high-quality solutions.

I offer consulting, training, and software development services in C, C++, Rust, Linux, and technologies for embedded and IoT systems.

Since 2014, I have been working as an independent software developer, taking on various projects.

As a trainer, I've organized and conducted numerous C++ and Rust courses, sharing best practices and methodologies.

I am committed to staying up-to-date with the latest industry trends and technologies, ensuring that I can provide the most relevant and valuable guidance to my clients and students.

# Work Experience (as independent consultant) \_\_\_

Bluewind S.r.l. Castelfranco Veneto, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT, TRAINER

2018 - Present

- Implemented drivers and firmware for various safety critical embedded systems for automotive, marine and and industrial products. Languages:
   C, C++, Rust.
- Organized C++ and Rust courses for about ten developers.

#### Fracarro Radioindustrie S.r.l.

Castelfranco Veneto, Italy

TRAINER

Organized an 80 hours Advanced C++ course for 4 developers.

### Fiam Utensili Pneumatici S.p.A.

2023-2024

Consultant

2

- I conducted code reviews in various C and C++ projects (PIC, STM32, Windows) to assess their needs for bug fixes, documentation, and maintainability.
- To facilitate the smooth transition of a resigning team member, I provided consultancy services to help documentating the code.

Texa S.p.A. Monastier, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT, TRAINER

2014 - 2023

- Developed C++ communication libraries (both embedded and server side) for an IoT automotive project to handle real-time remote diagnostic
  data of about 500 thousands vehicles.
- Organized multiple C++ courses between 2015 and 2022, a total of about 150 hours and 40 developers.

#### Spring Tech Innovations S.r.l.

Limena, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT

2022

• Developed C++ software for an home automation and alarm system.

Ferrous Systems GmbH

sering cermany

DEVELOPER

2022

• Developed Rust compiler tests for Ferrocene qualified toolchain.

MERMEC S.p.A.

Morgano, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT

2020 - 2022

• Developed C++ and C# software for surface inspection of steel products.

**ASTRA Yacht S.r.l.**Developer, Consultant

Monfalcone, Italy 2015 - 2022

• Developed C++ software for sailboat real-time performance analysis.

Qascom S.r.l.

TRAINER

Bassano del Grappa, Italy

• Organized a 45 hours C++ course for 20 developers working on GNSS and space cybersecurity systems.

2021

Salvagnini S.p.A. Sarego, Italy

2019 - 2020 TRAINER

• Organized a course on modern C++ and Test Driven Development, for a total of 24 hours and 10 developers.

Organized a course on Test Driven Development for C and C++, for a total of 24 hours and 10 developers.

Bassano del Grappa, Italy Ubilot S.r.l.

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT

• Developed C++ and C# software.

Adatta S.r.l.

TRAINER

2014 - 2018

· Coached a junior C++ developer.

Carel S.p.A. Brugine, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT 2014 - 2018)

• Developed C++ software and C Linux drivers for HVAC products.

**GM Trading srls** Borgoricco, Italy

DEVELOPER

• Developed (JavaScript) UI of an e-commerce website

### **Work Experience (employee)**

Vimage S.r.l. Mirano, Italy

LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jul 2007 - Jul 2014

- Coordinated and mentored the R&D team of up to 5 developers.
- Worked on different projects for museums, stores and events. Most projects involved interactive projections, touchscreens, touchless sensors and computer vision.
- Developed company's core C++ libraries for 2d and 3d games.
- Developed a company Linux distribution based on Gentoo Linux.

Nasch S.r.l. Padova, Italy

WER DEVELOPER Oct 2005 - Apr 2007

- Developed local companies websites (PHP and JavaScript).
- Developed a web tv platform (Flash and ActionScript 3)

### Education

#### Liceo Scientifico E. Majorana Mirano, Italy

SCIENTIFIC HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA WITH A SPECIALIZATION IN THE NATIONAL INFORMATICS PLAN (P.N.I.) 2001 - 2005

Università di Padova Padua, Italy

MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (INCOMPLETE) 2005 - 2006

Università Ca' Foscari Venezia Venice, Italy

BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (INCOMPLETE) 2006 - 2008

### Skills\_

TRAINER

**Programming tools and techniques** Git, gdb, Docker, NeoVim, CLion, TDD

**Programming Languages** C++, C, Rust, JavaScript, Python, Haskell, C#, Bash

Languages Italian, English

## Non-profit

CodingGym www.coding-gym.org Feb. 2018 - Present

· Conducted monthly free workshops, in Padova and Castelfco Veneto, assisting over 100 participants

· Designed exercises covering algorithms, data structures, and problem-solving for monthly workshops

I hereby authorize the use of my personal data in accordance to the GDPR 679/16 - European regulation on the protection of personal data.

JANUARY 23, 2024 ALESSANDRO PEZZATO · RÉSUMÉ 2